Hello everyone and welcome back
to another lesson here at English Pod.
My name is Marco and my
name is Catherine and today
Marco you and I are
talking about movies, right?
We're talking a little bit about movies
but mostly we're having a big argument.
Okay, I kind of like arguments.
Lots of great words
and phrases for you to
learn here in English
but we've got an upper
intermediate level lesson with some
people who are not getting along very well.
It's a couple, a guy in a girl and they're
having a fight as couples do so we're going
to be learning a lot of
the different language
that they are using in
this very heated debate.
So let's listen to this dialogue for the
first time and then we'll be right back.
Wow, the terrible movie is finally over.
Next time I'm picking the film because I
don't want to end up seeing a chick flick.
Well you should have picked in the end
you always complain about everything.
Not everything, just this film, even
the title is ridiculous and it's so long.
Those were the two
and a half most wasted
hours of my life so
much so that I'm thinking
about asking them to
give me my money back.
I'm thinking of taking you back home.
I thought we could have a nice
evening but you're always so negative.
I'm only complaining about
a movie that I could have
rented or bought and
then thrown in the garbage.
Do you see?
That's what I'm talking about.
I can't stand your sarcastic jokes anymore.
Next time go with your gay friend
who is more in touch with his feelings.
Well he's more of a man than you are.
At least he appreciates love stories.
Love stories, more like one night stands.
Don't criticize Mario or else I'll start
on those fat drunk friends of yours.
They're no saints.
My friends, fat?
What about those whales you call friends?
You're unbearable.
You can walk home.
I'm leaving.
Fine.
I think the guy was
exaggerating a little bit.
What do you think?
I think they were both exaggerating.
You know by the end
of an argument, both
people are saying things
that maybe they don't mean.
I think we'll talk a little bit more
about this towards the end of the show.
But now why don't we take
a look at language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
On language takeaway
today we have four words
and the first one that you probably saw in
the very first sentence is a chick flick.
Chick flick.
So first of all the word
chick means a woman.
It's slang and it's not very nice.
It's not very nice.
You know.
I mean between guys
you would use it as like
all this chick or that
chick but you wouldn't
really walk up to a girl
and call her a chick right?
Now you wouldn't say,
"Hey chick, what's up?
" That's not something
you want to say.
So chick is a slang
word for a girl or a
woman and that chick
flick is a girl's movie.
So a flick is a movie.
Yeah.
Another slang word.
Exactly.
So this is the slang phrase for flick.
So hey, Marco, what flicks are
showing at the movie theater?
Mm-hmm.
All right.
Yeah.
So movies.
So in the chick flick is
usually a romantic movie,
a drama, something
that's very, like beaches.
Beaches is a chick flick.
I don't know if you've ever seen that.
Um, also he's just not that into
you is one of those new chick flicks.
Like how to lose a guy in 10 days.
Yeah.
How to lose a guy in 10
days or the Devil Wears Prada.
Bright Wars.
Wow.
Lots of chicks.
I've actually never seen any one of
these except how to lose a guy in 10 days.
I've actually only seen that one.
All right.
So chick flick is a girl's
or woman's movie.
And next up we have a
word, a sarcastic word.
I want sarcastic jokes.
So sarcastic jokes or
somebody being sarcastic.
God, Marko, you're always so sarcastic.
So what would sarcasm sound like?
Um, yeah, he's a really funny.
All right.
So it's not really what you're saying.
It's kind of how you're saying it.
Right.
So it's kind of like by
saying he's really funny.
You're saying, yeah, he's a funny guy.
But if I say, oh,
he's really funny, I'm
saying he's not funny,
he's, he's being mean.
Yeah, he's a jerk.
That sarcasm is kind of one of those things
that it's a little bit difficult to learn
how to do or to actually get it
right, especially in English, right?
Yeah.
Marko, great explanation.
Exactly.
That's the way it goes.
Oh, yeah, you're so funny.
Wow.
You're amazing.
You should go to, you
went to sarcasm school.
So my parents might really mean happy.
Sorry.
Just kidding.
All right.
So apart from being sarcastic, you can
criticize someone like you're ever critical.
No.
All right.
Sorry.
I'll stop.
You're really into character right now.
All right.
So critical to criticize someone
is to, um, to complain about
them or just say that the things
that they do are not very good.
So you can criticize a person or a movie.
Yeah.
So this movie wasn't very good.
It wasn't funny.
The actors were bad.
It was really long.
Mm-hmm.
These are criticisms.
Criticisms.
All right.
Well, and then moving on, the girl was
finally tired of the guy in his complaints.
And she said he's unbearable.
Gosh.
You're unbearable.
So the root of this word is to be able
to, like, to stand something, to bear it.
And so if you're unbearable,
uh, something is unbearable.
You just can't stand it.
All right.
So you're tired of it.
You can't stand it.
She's, she thinks he's so unbearable.
She makes him get out of the car.
And she leaves.
Yeah.
She says you can walk home.
All right.
So that's an unbearable person, right?
Mm-hmm.
So, uh, we took a look at those
four main words here in our dialogue.
Uh, let's move on now to some of the
phrases that we found in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
This first one's a common
one, especially when
we talk about women and men and the
relationship between women and men.
We say about men that
maybe they should be more
in touch with their feelings
or their feminine side.
Yeah.
So if you're saying to
be more in touch with
your feminine side, what
exactly are you saying?
So the question, well, what you're saying
is that you want to be able to express your
feelings more or
you want to be able to
understand more about, uh, your,
your feminine side or something like this.
So, uh, to be in touch with
is, is more about yourself.
It's about self reflection
and self understanding.
So, so, uh, you could
say, I'm a very serious
person, but I want to make
some changes in my life.
So I'm trying to be more in touch
with my inner child, your inner child.
Mm.
All right.
So to be in touch
with, and it's usually
related to feelings to
something intangible.
Or to behavior.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
To behavior.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
Moving on.
Now a heated phrase, a one night stand.
Oh, I'll let you explain this one, Marco.
All right.
So a one night stand
is a casual and very
quick temporal, um, encounter
that's usually a sexual encounter.
It's romantic.
Right.
So it can be between,
um, two different people.
They meet each other
one night, um, they have
a relationship for one night only and
then they never see each other again.
So it's, uh, it's casual.
It's a casual, very good.
So yeah, you would
see this, you see this a
lot in shows like, you know,
sex in the city and all that.
Yeah, they have a lot of
one night stands in that show.
All right.
So a one night stand
and well, related to
this, uh, the girl was
criticizing his friends
and she said, they're no saints.
Okay.
So he could say this
in many different ways.
He's no saint.
She's no saint or I'm no saint.
You're no saint.
So a saint is a good person.
It's a, it's a word that we use in religion
to say someone who's like mother Teresa or
someone who's just really good
and kind and doesn't commit any sins.
Exactly.
And so to say, I'm no saint is to say,
well, I do bad things or I say bad things.
I'm not perfect.
Okay.
So he or they, they're no
saints, they do bad stuff too.
Yeah.
Very good.
So that's the way that you would use.
He's no saint.
They're no saints.
All right.
So I think now we should
listen to our dialogue
for the last time and
we'll be right back.
Wow, the terrible movie is finally over.
Next time I'm picking the film because I
don't want to end up seeing a chick flick.
Well, you should have picked in the
end, you always complain about everything.
Just this film, even the title
was ridiculous and it's so long.
Those were the two and a half
most wasted hours of my life.
So much so that I'm thinking about
asking them to give me my money back.
I'm thinking of taking you back home.
I thought we could have a nice
evening, but you're always so negative.
I'm only complaining about
a movie that I could have
rented or bought and
then thrown in the garbage.
You see, that's what I'm talking about.
I can't stand your sarcastic jokes anymore.
Next time, go with your gay friend
who is more in touch with his feelings.
Well, he's more of a man than you
are, at least he appreciates love stories.
Love stories, more like one night stands.
Don't criticize Mario or else I'll start
on those fat drunk friends of yours.
They're no saints.
My friends.
Fat?
What about those whales you call friends?
You're unbearable.
You can walk home.
I'm leaving.
Fine.
All right, so, Catherine,
is this an argument
that you would say is
typical among couples?
Or maybe people that are
probably about to break up, right?
Not couples that are happy, I would say.
But yeah, you definitely
have people who
are, well, I guess it's kind of
the battle of the sexes, right?
They have people who
are different genders and
so they don't always
understand each other.
You want to have your
girlfriends as a girl and
your girlfriends behave
and talk in a certain
way together and guys do the
same thing, but with their friends.
So sometimes you
have these clashes, these
interactions that are
negative and when people
are upset with each
other, they say mean things.
And especially, I think in this case, they
don't really like each other's friends.
Exactly.
Kind of a common thing, a
guy doesn't like his girlfriends'
friends because maybe they gossip
too much or something like that.
And the same thing
with the girls, right,
because a guy's friends
maybe drinks too much.
Drink too much.
It's played so many car games.
They're single.
So I think a lot of times
these problems also
have to do with the fact that when a
girl is with her girlfriend, she maybe acts
differently or when a
guy's with his guy friends.
And so that's weird
sometimes for the
relationship because you see your partner
acting differently with other people.
Right.
Do you like your boyfriend
or girlfriend friends?
Do you get in fights
about this kind of stuff?
Or you know what?
The in-laws.
Ooh, that's the whole number of situations.
That's the whole number of situations.
That's the movie.
Alright, so we want to
hear from you and also if
you have any questions
or comments suggestions.
Come to Englishpot.com and
you can leave it on our lessons
page or you can email us at
Englishpot@Praxaslanguage.com.
We hope to see you on our website in the
near future, please get in touch with us.
That's all for today.
Bye bye.
[MUSIC]